SURESH SIVANANTHAM

Preserve Lake Drive, Westchase, FL 33626 • Cell: 813-995-1939 • suresh.sivanantham@gmail.com https://github.com/v8-suresh • https://www.linkedin.com/in/sivananthamsuresh

Professional Summary

Programmer successful at managing teams, driving progress toward project milestones, quality assurance and on-time delivery. Offers 10 years in application development using modern web technologies.

Skills

Java, J2EE Oracle, mySQL, postgres, mongoDB

Javascript(ECMA 6), NodeJS Android, Cordova, Ionic

Spring, Struts, Hibernate, MyBatis, GWT GIT, SVN

Jersey REST Maven, Gradle, Ant

Angular(all versions), React, Redux Grunt, Gulp, Webpack

JQuery, Sencha ExtJS/Touch Windows, Unix, mac OS

Docker, Amazon Web Services Japanese Language Expert

Certifications

AWS Certified Developer - Associate.

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate.

Japanese Language Proficiency Test (JLPT) 2007 - Level 3. .

Sun Certified Java Programmer (SCJP) for Java Standard Edition – Java 5.0.

Work History

Senior Software Engineer, 08/2016 to Current

NIELSEN - OLDSMAR, FLORIDA

- Evaluated potential software products based on new and existing system development and migration requirements.
- Led a group of 6 engineers in the design, and development of Java, Angular and Docker based software solutions.
- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products.

- Modified existing software to correct errors, adapt to new hardware and improve performance.
- Collaborated with developers and performance engineers to enhance supportability and identify performance bottlenecks.
- Contributed to the jenkins shell script and mavel plugin codebase used in the automated deployment of software application.
- Built, tested and released highly efficient metadata driven component library.
- Reviewed project goals and objectives with the project manager and design team.
- Identified and suggested new technologies and tools for enhancing product value and increasing team productivity.

Senior Software Engineer, 01/2016 to 08/2016

American Express - Phoenix, Arizona, US

- Led a group of 8 engineers in the design, and development of Java, Angular, jQuery based software solutions.
- Evaluated multiple software solutions during early software architecture plotting and system migration planning stage.
- Oversaw major new enhancements to existing software systems.
- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products.
- Modified existing software to correct errors, adapt to new hardware and improve performance.
- Reviewed and approved all engineering, product and project scope documents prior to delivery.

Assistant Consultant, 03/2013 to 01/2016

Tata Consultancy Services - Chennai, India & Oldsmar, FL, USA

- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products.
- Led a group of 4 engineers in the design, and development of Java, GWT based software solutions.
- Streamlined deployment process by developing continuous integration tools.
- Modified existing software to correct errors, adapt to new hardware and improve performance.
- Worked closely with clients to establish problem specifications and system designs.
- Identified and suggested new technologies and tools for enhancing product value and increasing team productivity.
- Collaborated with product management to design, build and test systems.
- Developed code fixes and enhancements for inclusion in future code releases and patches.

Senior Software Engineer, 11/2009 to 02/2013

Wipro Technologies - Chennai, India & Tokyo, Japan

- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products.
- Evaluated potential software products based on new and existing system development and migration requirements.

- Collaborated with developers and performance engineers to enhance supportability and identify performance bottlenecks.
- Led a group of 3 engineers in the design, and development of Java, COBOL(unix) -based software solutions.
- Worked closely with clients to establish problem specifications and system designs.

Software Engineer, 07/2009 to 09/2009

Corporater Inc - Chennai, India

- Wrote maintainable and extensible code in a team environment.
- Implemented designs, including experimentation and multiple iterations.
- Modified existing software to correct errors, upgrade interfaces and improve performance.
- Rapidly prototyped new capabilities to confirm feasibility.
- Directed software design and development while remaining focused on client needs.
- Worked effectively with design teams to ensure software solutions elevated client side experience.
- Interfaced with business analysts, developers and technical support to determine the best requirement specifications.
- Worked closely with other team members to plan, design and develop robust solutions in a timely manner.

Programmer, 11/2006 to 07/2009

IVTL Infoview Technologies Pvt Ltd - Chennai, India

- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products.
- Modified existing software to correct errors, adapt to new hardware and improve performance.
- Developed Applications on Java, Oracle Platform using Struts, Spring frameworks.
- Worked closely with clients to establish problem specifications and system designs.

Education

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING: Electrical and Electronics, 2006

GKM College of Engineering - Chennai, India